export const CHEMISTRYA2015 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The negatively charged particle in an atom is the",
A: "Electron",
B: "Neutron",
C: "Positron",
D: "Proton",
answer: "A. Electron",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. How many orbits are contained in an atom with atomic number 13?",
A: "7",
B: "6",
C: "5",
D: "3",
answer: "C. 5",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The Van der waals’ forces are dominant intermolecular forces in_______?",
A: "Ammonium chloride",
B: "Chlorine",
C: "Sodium chloride",
D: "Water",
answer: "B. Chlorine",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The compound formed between 14X and 16Y is _______?",
A: "XY",
B: "XY2",
C: "X2Y",
D: "X4Y6",
answer: "B. XY2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The shape of a molecule of water is _______?",
A: "Non-linear",
B: "Octahedral",
C: "Pyramidal",
D: "Tetrahedral",
answer: "A. Non-linear",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A metallic ion Z2+ with an inert gas structure contains 18 electrons. How many protons are contained in this ion?",
A: "20",
B: "18",
C: "16",
D: "2",
answer: "A. 20",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following pairs of elements forms amphoteric oxides?",
A: "Be and Mg",
B: "Na and K",
C: "B and Al",
D: "Si and Pb",
answer: "D. Si and Pb",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following pairs of compounds belongs to the same homologous series?",
A: "C3H8 and  C3H6",
B: "C4H10 and  C5H10",
C: "C2H4 and C4H10",
D: "C2H6 and  C4H10",
answer: "D. C2H6 and C4H10",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The following transition metal ions would be coloured in aqueous solution except________?",
A: "Cr3+",
B: "Fe3+",
C: "Mn3+",
D: "Sc3+",
answer: "D. Sc3+",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The gas given off when ethanol reacts with sodium is",
A: "Carbon(IV)oxide",
B: "Hydrogen",
C: "Methane",
D: "Oxygen",
answer: "B. Hydrogen",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following halogens is solid at room temperature?",
A: "Bromine",
B: "Chlorine",
C: "Fluorine",
D: "Iodine",
answer: "D. Iodine",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The alkaline earth metals have similar chemical properties because________?",
A: "They are in the same period",
B: "Their salts are colourless",
C: "They have the same number of valence electrons",
D: "They are very reactive",
answer: "C. They have the same number of valence electrons",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The number of unpaired electrons in an atom of an element 8Q is _______?",
A: "2",
B: "4",
C: "6",
D: "8",
answer: "A. 2",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The bond formed when ammonia reacts with hydrogen ion to form ammonium ion is",
A: "Covalent",
B: "Dative",
C: "Hydrogen bond",
D: "Ionic",
answer: "B. Dative",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. To which group and period respectively does an element with 15 electrons belong?",
A: "3 and 3",
B: "3 and 5",
C: "5 and 3",
D: "5 and 5",
answer: "C. 5 and 3",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The shape of a graphite crystal is",
A: "Tetrahedral",
B: "Pyramidal",
C: "Octahedral",
D: "Hexagonal",
answer: "D. Hexagonal",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following oxides is ionic?",
A: "P4O10",
B: "MgO",
C: "Al2O3",
D: "SO2",
answer: "B. MgO",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following substances when boiled with an aqueous solution of sodium hydroxide would be hydrolyzed? \ni. Protein \nii. Fat \niii. Polythene",
A: "i",
B: "ii",
C: "i and ii",
D: "ii and iii",
answer: "B. ii",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following trioxonitrate(V) salts would decompose on heating to form a metal?",
A: "Cu(NO3)2",
B: "AgNO",
C: "Pb(NO3)2",
D: "KNO3",
answer: "B. AgNO3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Consider the following reaction equation: C2H4(g) + 3O2(g) → 2CO2(g) + 2H2O(g) The volume of CO2(g) produced at s.t.p when 0.05 moles of C2H4(g) was burnt in O2(g) is  [Molar Volume of gas = 22.4dm3]",
A: "1.12dm3",
B: "2.24dm3",
C: "3.72dm3",
D: "4.48dm3",
answer: "B. 2.24dm3",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The number of oxygen molecules present in 16.0g of the gas is ______? [Avogadro’s number = 6.02 x 1023]",
A: "6.02 x 1022",
B: "6.02 x 1023",
C: "3.01 x 1023",
D: "1.51 x 1023",
answer: "C. 3.01 x 1023",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Consider the following reaction equation: SO42-(aq) + 2H+(aq) + ye– → SO42-2(aq) + H2O(l). The value of y in the equation is",
A: "2",
B: "3",
C: "4",
D: "6",
answer: "A. 2",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The general gas equation was derived from______?",
A: "Boyle's and Gay Lussac's laws",
B: "Boyle's and Graham's laws",
C: "Boyle's and Charles' laws",
D: "Dalton's atomic theory",
answer: "C. Boyle's and Charles' laws",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following statements about intermolecular distances and cohesive forces between gas is correct? They are",
A: "Both large",
B: "Both negligible",
C: "Constant and negligible",
D: "Large and negligible",
answer: "D. Large and negligible",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The vapour pressure of a liquid depends on \nI. Temperature \nII. rate of condensation \nIII. Cohesive forces holding the particles together",
A: "I",
B: "I and II",
C: "I and III",
D: "II and III",
answer: "C. II and III",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following gases will diffuse most rapidly? [H = 1.00, C = 12.0, O = 16.0, S = 32.0, Cl = 35.5]",
A: "Cl2",
B: "SO2",
C: "CH4",
D: "C2H6",
answer: "C. CH4",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. When a reaction is endothermic,",
A: "Enthalpy change,ΔH is negative",
B: "Heat content of a product is less than the heat content of a reactant",
C: "Heat content of reactants is less than the heat content of product",
D: "The reaction is non-spontaneous",
answer: "C. Heat content of reactants is less than the heat content of product",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The following diagram illustrates the rate curve that was obtained when Mg reacted with excess dilute HCl. The diagram became horizontal at X because",
A: "The reaction was slowed down",
B: "All the dilute HCl has reacted",
C: "All the Mg has reacted",
D: "Hydrogen gas is produced at a steady rate",
answer: "C. All the Mg has reacted",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. An example of an acid salt is",
A: "CH3COOONa",
B: "Mg(OH)Cl",
C: "NaHSO4",
D: "(NH4)2SO4",
answer: "D. (NH4)2SO4",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following oxides can be reduced by hydrogen?",
A: "Aluminum oxide",
B: "Magnesium oxide",
C: "Sodium oxide",
D: "Silver oxide",
answer: "D. Silver oxide",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Solubility is practically applied in",
A: "Fractional distillation",
B: "The determination of pH",
C: "The determination of saturation in hydrocarbons",
D: "Solvent extraction",
answer: "D. Solvent extraction",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which of the following compounds is the least soluble in water?",
A: "CaCl2",
B: "CaSO4",
C: "NaCl",
D: "Na2SO4",
answer: "B. CaSO4",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. A  compound which dissolves readily in organic solvent would",
A: "Be a covalent compound",
B: "Have strong electrostatic forces of attraction",
C: "have a high melting point",
D: "Conduct electricity in molten state",
answer: "A. Be a covalent compound",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. A change in the temperature of a saturated solution disturbs the equilibrium between the",
A: "Undissolved solute and the solvent",
B: "Dissolved solute and the solvent",
C: "Dissolved solute and the undissolved solute",
D: "Dissolved solute and the solution",
answer: "C. Dissolved solute and the undissolved solute",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following statements about an electrochemical cell is correct? Oxidation occurs",
A: "At the anode",
B: "At the cathode",
C: "Through the salt bridge",
D: "In the aqueous solution",
answer: "A. At the anode",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Consider the following reaction equation: CuO(s) + H2(g) Cu(s) + H2O(l) Which substance is oxidized?",
A: "Cu",
B: "CuO",
C: "H2",
D: "H2O",
answer: "C. H2",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following metals is the strongest reducing agent?",
A: "Sodium",
B: "Silver",
C: "Potassium",
D: "Copper",
answer: "C. Potassium",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The complete hydrogenation of benzene gives",
A: "Cyclohexene",
B: "Cyclohexane",
C: "Hexene",
D: "Hexane",
answer: "B. Cyclohexane",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. A compound has an empirical formula CH2O and a molecular mass of 90. Determine the molecular formula [H = 1.00, C = 12.0, O = 16.0]",
A: "C4H10O2",
B: "C3H10O2",
C: "C3H6O3",
D: "C2H2O4",
answer: "C. C3H6O3",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following reactions would take place when concentrated sodium hydroxide solution is added to palm oil?",
A: "Esterification",
B: "Neutralization",
C: "Polymerization",
D: "Saponification",
answer: "D. Saponification",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Starch could be converted to glucose by the process of",
A: "Condensation",
B: "Dehydration",
C: "Fermentation",
D: "Hydrolysis",
answer: "D. Hydrolysis",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following compounds is a secondary alkanol?",
A: "Ethanol",
B: "2-methylbutan-2-ol",
C: "3-methylpentan-2-ol",
D: "Propan-1-ol",
answer: "C. 3-methylpentan-2-ol",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the following substances is a heavy chemical?",
A: "Ammonia",
B: "Barim Hydroxide",
C: "Hydrochloric acid",
D: "Tetraoxosulphate(VI)acid",
answer: "D. Tetraoxosulphate(VI)acid",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following process does not take place in domestic water treatment?",
A: "Chlorination",
B: "Flocculation",
C: "Neutralization",
D: "Sedimentation",
answer: "C. Neutralization",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. A substance responsible for the sour taste of unripe oranges is",
A: "Alkene",
B: "Alkanol",
C: "Alkanoic acid",
D: "Alkanoate",
answer: "C. Alkanoic acid",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following products of biotechnology can be used as a fuel in place of petrol?",
A: "Butane",
B: "Ethanol",
C: "Ethene",
D: "Propanol",
answer: "B. Ethanol",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Which of the following polymers in thermosetting?",
A: "Bakelite",
B: "Nylon",
C: "Polypropene",
D: "Polystyrene",
answer: "A. Bakelite",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following gases is monoatomic?",
A: "Argon",
B: "Chlorine",
C: "Nitrogen",
D: "Oxygen",
answer: "A. Argon",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The correct balanced equation for the reaction between aluminum metal and hot concentrated tetraoxosulphate(VI)acid is ?",
A: "2AI(s)+ 6H2SO4(l)→AI2(SO4)3(aq)+ 6H2O(l)+ 3SO2(g)",
B: "2AI(s)+ 3H2SO4(l)→AI2(SO4)3(aq)+ 3H2O(l)+ 3SO2(g)",
C: "2AI(s)+ 4H2SO4(l)→AI2(SO4)3(aq)+ 8H2O(l)+ 4SO2(g)",
D: "2AI(s)+ 3H2SO4(l)→AI2(SO4)3(aq)+ 6H2O(l)+ 3SO2(g)",
answer: "A. 2AI(s)+ 6H2SO4(l)→AI2(SO4)3(aq)+ 6H2O(l)+ 3SO2(g)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Consider the following equilibrium system: 2SO2(g) + O2(g) ⇌ 2SO3(g) The addition of more O2(g) to the system will shift the equilibrium position to the",
A: "Right leading to the production of more SO3(g)",
B: "Right leading to the production of more SO2(g)",
C: "Left leading to the production of more SO2(g)",
D: "Left leading to the production of more SO3(g)",
answer: "A. Right leading to the production of more SO3(g)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]